<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>BCE Vacancies</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/SearchJobs/?1202=%5B649%2C650%2C802%5D&amp;1202_format=1471&amp;listFilterMode=1&amp;jobRecordsPerPage=10&amp;</link><description>Job Search | European Central Bank</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><image><url>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/portal/6/favicon.ico</url><title>BCE Vacancies</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/SearchJobs/?1202=%5B649%2C650%2C802%5D&amp;1202_format=1471&amp;listFilterMode=1&amp;jobRecordsPerPage=10&amp;</link></image><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:51:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Compliance and Governance Analysts</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Compliance-and-Governance-Analysts/2990</link><description>Legal Analysis &amp; Advice - Deadline: 11-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Compliance and Governance Analysts</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Legal Analysis & Advice</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i>Entry/early career</i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Secretariat</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>11-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract, which may be extended subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    E/F (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,167 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Compliance and Governance
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    11.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Compliance and Governance Division in the Directorate General Secretariat. Our Division, comprising 17 members of staff, supports the Executive Board and the Chief Compliance and Governance Officer in protecting the integrity and reputation of the ECB by promoting ethical standards of behaviour within the institution and by strengthening its accountability and transparency. We are currently reviewing our ethical rules, establishing processes for retaliation protection, consolidating the procedures for disclosure of ECB documents to national authorities and developing our internal processes for the management of conduct risk.In your role as a Compliance and Governance Analyst, you will be part of three teams responsible for developing and implementing the ECB’s regimes for ethics and access to documents and conducting regular reviews to ensure that they remain up to date; taking the necessary measures to promote and monitor compliance with the ECB’s ethics regime, including providing ongoing training and individual advice and guidance; supporting the enhancement and harmonisation of ethics and compliance standards within the Eurosystem and European banking supervision; coordinating requests and queries received from the European Ombudsman; performing the secretary function for the ECB’s Audit and Ethics Committees; and supporting the Ethics and Compliance Officers Task Force, which is made up of chief compliance or ethics officers from the Eurosystem and European banking supervision and helps – based on practical experience – to further enhance and harmonise ethics and compliance standards at the level of the Eurosystem and European banking supervision.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a Compliance and Governance Analyst you will:analyse data and information from a variety of sources and facilitate legal assessments by researching relevant precedents, benchmarking, identifying patterns, case law and other existing information; contribute to the preparation of the Division’s annual reports;facilitate the drafting of legal assessments, replies to requests for ethical advice, access to documents and follow-ups to European Ombudsman cases/queries concerning complaints against the ECB by collecting relevant information and input on the matter and proposing a first draft;build and maintain database infrastructures templates and manuals and support the development of analytical tools;provide support to the Chief Compliance and Governance Officer for the coordination of high-level ECB committee/task force meetings and dedicated tasks; liaise with counterparts in the ECB, Eurosystem and European banking supervision with a view to building and maintaining productive relationships with internal and external stakeholders and creating value for the ECB through collaborative exchanges that reach across hierarchies, specialisations and organisational units.The position offers you excellent opportunities to contribute to protecting the ECB’s integrity and reputation by enhancing its accountability and transparency and promoting good administration and good governance standards, as well as ethical standards of behaviour, within the institution. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential: a bachelor’s degree or equivalent in law or another relevant field (click here for details on degree equivalences);in addition to the above, a minimum of one year’s experience with analysing, benchmarking and interpreting legal texts and conducting legal research in the areas of ethics, good governance and transparency; proven skills in the use of databases and analytical tools;an ability to work independently under minimal supervision;good drafting skills and an ability to convey complex information in a clear, simple and concise manner; an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired: a clear understanding of the mission, tasks and responsibilities of the ECB;good knowledge of the ECB’s confidentiality and transparency regime and of the ECB’s ethical rules and provisions;awareness of trends and best practices in ethical, transparency and governance matters;experience with fact-finding or conduct risk monitoring, including data protection aspects.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are motivated to contribute to the ECB’s mission, to serve the citizens of the EU as a member of a public institution and to work with colleagues from all over Europe.You are motivated to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Further information


The contracts offered will be fixed-term, the appointment being for 12 months as of the exact starting date of the selected person.Temporary appointments may be extended or made permanent subject to organisational needs and budgetary constraints. This may result in a staff member with a non-convertible fixed-term contract being offered a convertible contract in accordance with the ECB Conditions of Employment. For additional information on this specific vacancy, you can speak to the hiring manager, Margarita Louisa Karydi, on +49 (0)69 1344 6842 between 12:00 and 13:00 on Monday, 25 January.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position will include a written exercise, a presentation and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Compliance-and-Governance-Analysts/2990</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:51:33 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawyer-Linguist with Estonian as main language</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Lawyer-Linguist-with-Estonian-as-main-language/2786</link><description>Legal Analysis &amp; Advice - Deadline: 05-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Lawyer-Linguist with Estonian as main language</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Legal Analysis & Advice</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i>Experienced</i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Legal Services</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>05-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract which may be converted into a permanent contract after three years subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    F/G (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,914 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Law and Linguistics
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    05.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Legislation Division in the Directorate General Legal Services. Our Division has approximately 40 staff members and is responsible for preparing the ECB’s legal acts in the official EU languages, for drafting legal documents and ensuring their legal, linguistic and terminological consistency and for publishing and disseminating the ECB’s legal framework and other legal publications. In your role as Lawyer-Linguist with Estonian as your main language, you will be primarily responsible for translating ECB legal acts and other legal texts from English into Estonian and for revising translations of such texts provided by external suppliers. The legal acts and texts relate to both central banking and banking supervision. You will work closely with other lawyer-linguists and legal counsels in the Directorate General Legal Services and with staff in a number of the ECB’s other business areas.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a Lawyer-Linguist with Estonian as main language you will:translate draft ECB legal acts and other legal texts from English into Estonian;revise Estonian translations of ECB legal acts and other legal texts;translate legal texts from Estonian into English for internal working purposes and revise Estonian to English translations of national laws, documents related to court proceedings and other legal texts;contribute to the drafting of ECB legal acts;liaise with counterparts within the ECB, Eesti Pank and other relevant EU and national institutions; engage in Legislation Division projects related to the development and modernisation of the ECB lawyer-linguist function, such as knowledge management, technology, etc.The position offers you excellent opportunities to contribute to the quality of ECB legal acts. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential: - a mastery-level command (i.e. native-speaker standard) of Estonian;- an advanced (C1) command of English, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages;- a master’s degree in law or equivalent obtained at a university in Estonia (click here for details on degree equivalences);- in addition to the above, at least two years’ proven professional experience in translating legal, financial or economic texts from English into Estonian.Desired: - proven professional experience in drafting and/or translating legal acts or litigation-related documentation or working as a lawyer-linguist, preferably with another EU institution;- a good knowledge of EU, financial and supervisory law;- an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are aware of your strengths and areas for development and know what motivates you to perform at your highest level.You are motivated to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Working modalities


To enable the Section to maintain its business continuity capability, you will occasionally be expected to perform work during non-standard working hours and work at the ECB’s standby sites.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position will include a written exercise, a presentation and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Lawyer-Linguist-with-Estonian-as-main-language/2786</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:51:33 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>