<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>BCE Vacancies</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/SearchJobs/?jobRecordsPerPage=10&amp;jobOffset=0</link><description>Job Search | European Central Bank</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><image><url>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/portal/6/favicon.ico</url><title>BCE Vacancies</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/SearchJobs/?jobRecordsPerPage=10&amp;jobOffset=0</link></image><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Business Analysis Specialists</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Business-Analysis-Specialists/2746</link><description>Information Technology - Deadline: 05-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Business Analysis Specialists</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Information Technology</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i></i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Information Systems</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>05-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract which may be converted into a permanent contract after three years subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    E/F (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,167 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Business Analysis
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    05.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Supervisory Technologies and Data Section of the Prudential Domain Services Division in the Directorate General Information Systems. We are a team of around 30 information technology (IT) professionals delivering tailored IT solutions for financial stability, statistics and ECB Banking Supervision.In your role as a Business Analysis Specialist, you will be part of a team which ‒ together with external contractors ‒ is responsible for developing, maintaining and supporting IT solutions in line with business needs. You will work closely and collaboratively with business customers, technical teams (e.g. development, testing, integration, maintenance and support teams) and external stakeholders. We are currently seeking to fill two Business Analysis Specialist positions.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a Business Analysis Specialist you will:engage and collaborate with the IT Project Manager on business opportunities and challenges ahead, documenting business needs (including acceptance criteria), modelling business processes and supporting the creation of data models;collaborate with business customers to understand, elicit and clarify requirements, especially in terms of testability, consistency and completeness;support the preparation and execution of software testing activities; support supplier management, purchasing, procurement and budget monitoring activities;contribute to the organisation of meetings, training and large-scale workshops with internal and/or external participants, including supporting the preparation of agendas, minutes and action points;produce and review deliverables (e.g. requirements documents, manuals, guidance documents, training materials), support the preparation of documentation (e.g. briefings, notes, presentations, external publications and dossiers for the governing bodies), and manage information (e.g. in Darwin, PPM, Jira or HP ALM), ensuring it is up to date;contribute to the development of processes and tools for analysis and reporting purposes to support quality assurance in supervisory stress tests;support the administration of frequently asked questions processes for supervisory stress tests;support central communication with internal and external stakeholders, and support supervisory stress test teams with the preparation of reports on content.The position offers you excellent opportunities to gain valuable insights into banking supervision functions and to contribute to the establishment of supervisory processes and methodologies in Europe. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential: a bachelor’s degree or equivalent in economics, business administration, computer science or another relevant field (click here for details on degree equivalences);in addition to the above, a minimum of three and ideally five or more years’ experience in the field of business analysis, information management, procurement, resource management, budget monitoring or IT project execution processes;a sound understanding of Project Management Methodology (PM2) and/or the six knowledge areas of the Business Analysis Body of Knowledge® (BABOK®);professional work experience in a project management office (PMO);experience in using Jira Software for issue tracking, workflow management, and HP ALM for requirements or test management;proficiency in using Microsoft Office (e.g. Word, Excel, PowerPoint); strong customer orientation and the ability to manage stress;an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired: experience in stress testing, a finance environment, a fast-paced multicultural environment, international projects or working experience in European institutions;a good understanding of ECB banking supervision business processes and the ability to act as bridge between business customers and IT technical teams;knowledge of the techniques and methods involved in requirements engineering and the ability to quickly pick up requirements management tools (e.g. HP ALM); exposure to IT project management during which projects were successfully managed, ideally large, complex, custom-built application development projects;project management certification (e.g. PM2, PMI) and/or business analysis certification (e.g. CBAP®);experience in liaising with legal, controlling and procurement functions. You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are motivated to contribute to the ECB’s mission, to serve the citizens of the EU as a member of a public institution and to work with colleagues from all over Europe.You are motivated to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Working modalities


To enable the Section to maintain its business continuity capability, you will occasionally be expected to perform work during non-standard working hours.We are willing to discuss part-time arrangements.




Further information


For additional information on this specific vacancy, you can speak to the Team Lead, Ana Padrão, on +49 (0)69 1344 7944 between 14:30 and 15:30 on Friday, 29 January 2021.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position will include a written exercise, a presentation and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Business-Analysis-Specialists/2746</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Compliance and Governance Analysts</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Compliance-and-Governance-Analysts/2990</link><description>Legal Analysis &amp; Advice - Deadline: 11-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Compliance and Governance Analysts</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Legal Analysis & Advice</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i>Entry/early career</i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Secretariat</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>11-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract, which may be extended subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    E/F (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,167 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Compliance and Governance
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    11.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Compliance and Governance Division in the Directorate General Secretariat. Our Division, comprising 17 members of staff, supports the Executive Board and the Chief Compliance and Governance Officer in protecting the integrity and reputation of the ECB by promoting ethical standards of behaviour within the institution and by strengthening its accountability and transparency. We are currently reviewing our ethical rules, establishing processes for retaliation protection, consolidating the procedures for disclosure of ECB documents to national authorities and developing our internal processes for the management of conduct risk.In your role as a Compliance and Governance Analyst, you will be part of three teams responsible for developing and implementing the ECB’s regimes for ethics and access to documents and conducting regular reviews to ensure that they remain up to date; taking the necessary measures to promote and monitor compliance with the ECB’s ethics regime, including providing ongoing training and individual advice and guidance; supporting the enhancement and harmonisation of ethics and compliance standards within the Eurosystem and European banking supervision; coordinating requests and queries received from the European Ombudsman; performing the secretary function for the ECB’s Audit and Ethics Committees; and supporting the Ethics and Compliance Officers Task Force, which is made up of chief compliance or ethics officers from the Eurosystem and European banking supervision and helps – based on practical experience – to further enhance and harmonise ethics and compliance standards at the level of the Eurosystem and European banking supervision.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a Compliance and Governance Analyst you will:analyse data and information from a variety of sources and facilitate legal assessments by researching relevant precedents, benchmarking, identifying patterns, case law and other existing information; contribute to the preparation of the Division’s annual reports;facilitate the drafting of legal assessments, replies to requests for ethical advice, access to documents and follow-ups to European Ombudsman cases/queries concerning complaints against the ECB by collecting relevant information and input on the matter and proposing a first draft;build and maintain database infrastructures templates and manuals and support the development of analytical tools;provide support to the Chief Compliance and Governance Officer for the coordination of high-level ECB committee/task force meetings and dedicated tasks; liaise with counterparts in the ECB, Eurosystem and European banking supervision with a view to building and maintaining productive relationships with internal and external stakeholders and creating value for the ECB through collaborative exchanges that reach across hierarchies, specialisations and organisational units.The position offers you excellent opportunities to contribute to protecting the ECB’s integrity and reputation by enhancing its accountability and transparency and promoting good administration and good governance standards, as well as ethical standards of behaviour, within the institution. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential: a bachelor’s degree or equivalent in law or another relevant field (click here for details on degree equivalences);in addition to the above, a minimum of one year’s experience with analysing, benchmarking and interpreting legal texts and conducting legal research in the areas of ethics, good governance and transparency; proven skills in the use of databases and analytical tools;an ability to work independently under minimal supervision;good drafting skills and an ability to convey complex information in a clear, simple and concise manner; an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired: a clear understanding of the mission, tasks and responsibilities of the ECB;good knowledge of the ECB’s confidentiality and transparency regime and of the ECB’s ethical rules and provisions;awareness of trends and best practices in ethical, transparency and governance matters;experience with fact-finding or conduct risk monitoring, including data protection aspects.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are motivated to contribute to the ECB’s mission, to serve the citizens of the EU as a member of a public institution and to work with colleagues from all over Europe.You are motivated to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Further information


The contracts offered will be fixed-term, the appointment being for 12 months as of the exact starting date of the selected person.Temporary appointments may be extended or made permanent subject to organisational needs and budgetary constraints. This may result in a staff member with a non-convertible fixed-term contract being offered a convertible contract in accordance with the ECB Conditions of Employment. For additional information on this specific vacancy, you can speak to the hiring manager, Margarita Louisa Karydi, on +49 (0)69 1344 6842 between 12:00 and 13:00 on Monday, 25 January.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position will include a written exercise, a presentation and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Compliance-and-Governance-Analysts/2990</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Economist</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Economist/3005</link><description>Analysis and Policy Advice - Deadline: 11-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Economist</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Analysis and Policy Advice</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i></i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Monetary Policy</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>11-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Short-term contract, which may be extended to up to 36 months subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Contract end date


                                    31.03.2022
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals working for the international public sector organisation or EU organisations performing central banking or banking supervision tasks. Your current contract must extend at least 1 year beyond the end of the potential employment at the ECB
                                



Salary


                                    F/G (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,914 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Economics and Monetary Policy
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    11.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Monetary Analysis Division in the Directorate General Monetary Policy. Our Division is responsible for monitoring and analysing monetary and financial developments in the euro area from a microeconomic and macroeconomic perspective, focusing on monetary and credit aggregates. It also monitors, analyses and conducts, from a monetary policy perspective, studies on the bank lending channel of monetary policy, covering loans, lending rates, funding conditions, surveys of lending policies and individual bank information. We are currently working on the monetary policy response to the coronavirus (COVID-19) crisis and on the ECB’s strategy review.In your role as Economist in the Bank Lending Conditions Section, you will be part of a team of 20 members of staff working on the calibration of monetary policy measures, including non-standard measures, in view of how they affect the economy through the banking system. We monitor and conduct regular analysis of the transmission of monetary policy via banks, including its interaction with microprudential and macroprudential policies. We also have primary responsibility for the ECB’s bank lending survey.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As an Economist you will:assess the monetary policy transmission mechanism in the euro area, with a specific focus on the analysis of transmission via banks from both a microeconomic and a macroeconomic perspective;contribute to the preparation of material related to monetary policy decisions and communication, including (i) analyses of money and credit developments, (ii) material for briefing members of the Executive Board and senior management in preparation for meetings of the Governing Council and (iii) policy papers, speeches, empirical and conceptual studies, and other publications;develop and apply financial intermediation models for monetary policy analysis;contribute to the coordination of the Division’s work, in particular the preparation of major reports for the Executive Board and the Governing Council as well as research work.The position offers you excellent opportunities to contribute to the assessment of the monetary policy transmission mechanism via banks and apply state-of-the-art econometric models to policy-relevant issues. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential: a master’s degree or equivalent in economics or another relevant field (click here for details on degree equivalences);in addition to the above, a minimum of seven years of relevant working experience;sound knowledge of statistical and econometric techniques for analytical purposes;experience in preparing policy-related briefing and analytical material;very good writing skills and the ability to draft well-structured notes within strict deadlines;the ability to identify and address policy issues and to present analytical findings both in non-technical terms to policymakers and in technical terms at academic conferences;an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired: a PhD, together with a research and publication record;a sound academic record in applied microeconomics or macroeconomics related to banking and the monetary policy transmission mechanism.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are motivated to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Further information


The contract(s) offered will be short-term ESCB/IO, the appointment being for 12 months as of the exact starting date of the selected person, extendable to up to 36 months.For additional information on this specific vacancy, you can contact Carlo Altavilla, Head of the Bank Lending Conditions Section (Carlo.Altavilla@ecb.europa.eu), and if necessary arrange a telephone discussion.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position will include a presentation and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Economist/3005</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Environmental Specialist</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Environmental-Specialist/2982</link><description>Organisational Solutions - Deadline: 04-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Environmental Specialist</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Organisational Solutions</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i></i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Administration</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>04-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract, which may be extended subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Contract end date


                                    01.07.2022
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    E/F (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,167 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Organisational Excellence
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    04.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Administrative Services Division in the Directorate Administration. Our Directorate has around 200 staff. It manages the ECB’s infrastructure, technical facilities and security arrangements, operates the ECB’s premises, and carries out medium-term spatial requirement planning and project management for ECB buildings. It also coordinates the ECB’s environmental management system (EMS), as well as all occupational health and safety activities.In your role as an Environmental Specialist in the Green ECB team, you will work closely with and support the ECB’s Environmental Officer, coordinating with colleagues in other parts of the Directorate (particularly the Facility Management, Corporate Real Estate and Administrative Services teams). You will also interact with communications, IT and procurement experts from other business areas, as well as environmental ambassadors from across the ECB. You will also collaborate closely with external service providers on specific projects and initiatives, ensuring that shared environmental and business objectives are achieved.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As an Environmental Specialist, you will:support the maintenance and development of the ECB’s environmental management system, which has been certified as complying with ISO 14001 and is registered with the EU’s Eco Management and Audit Scheme (EMAS);collect and analyse environmental data from various sources, develop and monitor environmental key performance indicators, and use data to produce engaging and effective communication material, management reports and dashboards;draft and review EMS-related documentation, information and reports aimed at various target groups (including senior management and external stakeholders);support the performance of environmental site checks and the carrying-out of follow-up actions (such as the drafting of reports, the provision of regular briefings on the status quo, and the implementation of corrective or preventive measures);research, analyse and present information from diverse and reliable sources to support the development of various aspects and elements of the EMS;assist with the development of EMS objectives and measures, the review and analysis of issues and trends, and the preparation of evaluations and proposals for further improvement;help to coordinate the involvement of relevant internal and external stakeholders in the implementation and further development of the EMS;support and facilitate the development and implementation of awareness-raising, communication and engagement campaigns;help to integrate environmental and/or sustainability-related considerations into public procurement processes and procedures;assist the environmental ambassadors in the various ECB business areas with the fulfilment of their mandates;support the ECB’s contributions to interinstitutional networks, events and working groups in the field of environmental management;help to manage documentation and data on the ECB’s dedicated information management and internal communication platforms;assist with the management of external service providers.This position will provide excellent opportunities to develop new tools and processes with a view to optimising the ECB’s environmental performance. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens.




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential:a bachelor’s degree or equivalent in environmental sciences, environmental management, sustainability, business administration, communication, international relations or another relevant field (click here for details on degree equivalences);in addition to the above, at least two years of professional experience in a relevant field (i.e. work relating to (i) the maintenance and development of environmental management systems, (ii) compliance with the requirements of ISO 14001 or EMAS, (iii) environmental/sustainability reporting or (iv) the development and implementation of awareness-raising and engagement campaigns on environmental/sustainability-related issues);a solid understanding of the science behind climate change, the interdependencies between the various systems that are affected by climate change, and the mitigation measures that are needed at the various micro and macro levels;an understanding of carbon accounting methodologies (such as the Greenhouse Gas Protocol, the Bilan Carbone or ISO 14064) and emission reduction strategies (such as the Science-Based Targets methodology);strong communication and presentation skills, gained in a multicultural environment, and the ability to engage with a range of different internal and external stakeholders, including senior management and staff;professional experience of collecting, analysing and reporting environmental data and facilitating data collection processes and procedures;practical experience of carrying out environmental/sustainability reporting in line with recognised standards and guidelines (such as those of the Global Reporting Initiative or EMAS) and integrating environmental, social and governance factors into organisational processes and reporting;familiarity with green procurement processes;an advanced knowledge of MS Office (particularly Excel, PowerPoint and Word);an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired:familiarity with digital and non-digital communication and collaboration tools;experience of managing contracts and relationships with external suppliers;professional experience of organising, facilitating and supporting training, meetings, workshops, committees, awareness-raising campaigns and events dealing with environmental and sustainability-related topics;knowledge of document management systems such as OpenText Livelink;an intermediate (B1) command of German.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are motivated to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Working modalities


We are willing to discuss part-time arrangements.




Further information


The formal title for this position will be Facility Management Specialist.Temporary appointments may be extended or made permanent subject to organisational needs and budgetary constraints. This may result in a staff member with a non-convertible fixed-term contract being offered a convertible contract in accordance with the ECB Conditions of Employment.The contract offered will be fixed-term, the appointment being for 13 months as of the exact starting date of the selected person.For additional information on this specific vacancy, you can speak to the hiring manager, Susanne Schröder, on +49 (0)172 1322192 between 15:30 and 16:30 on Tuesday, 26 January.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position will include a written exercise, a presentation and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Environmental-Specialist/2982</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawyer-Linguist with Estonian as main language</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Lawyer-Linguist-with-Estonian-as-main-language/2786</link><description>Legal Analysis &amp; Advice - Deadline: 05-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Lawyer-Linguist with Estonian as main language</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Legal Analysis & Advice</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i>Experienced</i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Legal Services</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>05-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract which may be converted into a permanent contract after three years subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    F/G (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,914 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Law and Linguistics
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    05.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Legislation Division in the Directorate General Legal Services. Our Division has approximately 40 staff members and is responsible for preparing the ECB’s legal acts in the official EU languages, for drafting legal documents and ensuring their legal, linguistic and terminological consistency and for publishing and disseminating the ECB’s legal framework and other legal publications. In your role as Lawyer-Linguist with Estonian as your main language, you will be primarily responsible for translating ECB legal acts and other legal texts from English into Estonian and for revising translations of such texts provided by external suppliers. The legal acts and texts relate to both central banking and banking supervision. You will work closely with other lawyer-linguists and legal counsels in the Directorate General Legal Services and with staff in a number of the ECB’s other business areas.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a Lawyer-Linguist with Estonian as main language you will:translate draft ECB legal acts and other legal texts from English into Estonian;revise Estonian translations of ECB legal acts and other legal texts;translate legal texts from Estonian into English for internal working purposes and revise Estonian to English translations of national laws, documents related to court proceedings and other legal texts;contribute to the drafting of ECB legal acts;liaise with counterparts within the ECB, Eesti Pank and other relevant EU and national institutions; engage in Legislation Division projects related to the development and modernisation of the ECB lawyer-linguist function, such as knowledge management, technology, etc.The position offers you excellent opportunities to contribute to the quality of ECB legal acts. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential: - a mastery-level command (i.e. native-speaker standard) of Estonian;- an advanced (C1) command of English, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages;- a master’s degree in law or equivalent obtained at a university in Estonia (click here for details on degree equivalences);- in addition to the above, at least two years’ proven professional experience in translating legal, financial or economic texts from English into Estonian.Desired: - proven professional experience in drafting and/or translating legal acts or litigation-related documentation or working as a lawyer-linguist, preferably with another EU institution;- a good knowledge of EU, financial and supervisory law;- an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are aware of your strengths and areas for development and know what motivates you to perform at your highest level.You are motivated to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Working modalities


To enable the Section to maintain its business continuity capability, you will occasionally be expected to perform work during non-standard working hours and work at the ECB’s standby sites.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position will include a written exercise, a presentation and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Lawyer-Linguist-with-Estonian-as-main-language/2786</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Market Infrastructure Specialist</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Market-Infrastructure-Specialist/2922</link><description>Fin. Markets &amp; Market Infrastructure Ops - Deadline: 04-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Market Infrastructure Specialist</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Fin. Markets & Market Infrastructure Ops</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i></i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Market Infrastructure & Payments</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>04-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract which may be converted into a permanent contract after three years subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    E/F (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,167 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Financial Market Management
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



On-call?


                                    Yes
                                



Shift?


                                    Yes
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    04.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Market Infrastructure Management Division in the Directorate General Market Infrastructure and Payments. Our Directorate General has around 140 staff, who seek to ensure that Europe’s financial markets can rely on safe and efficient market infrastructure, while embracing innovation and contributing to further European integration. Our responsibilities are threefold: we provide payment and securities settlement infrastructure under the TARGET Services brand; we monitor the performance of financial market infrastructure and payment instruments; and we work with the financial sector to promote innovation and the harmonisation of business practices across Europe.In your role as a Market Infrastructure Specialist, you will be part of a team of around 30 staff who are responsible for managing, analysing and operating the Eurosystem’s cash and securities settlement infrastructure (TARGET2, TIPS and T2S). The Division coordinates the daily operations of those three systems across the European System of Central Banks, as well as coordinating with other relevant stakeholders. In addition, we run the ECB’s own TARGET2 component, providing all necessary support to our clients. We also develop and carry out analysis of the business operations of our platforms, and we ensure that those platforms comply with all applicable regulatory and legal frameworks and rules. The Division also provides assistance to various teams working on large-scale Eurosystem projects and initiatives in the area of market infrastructure and payments (such as the TARGET2/T2S consolidation project and the Eurosystem Collateral Management System).You will join a dynamic team working on key market infrastructure issues at European level, providing support to the operational team responsible for TARGET Services and ensuring that our market infrastructure complies with all relevant frameworks and rules.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a Market Infrastructure Specialist in the Market Infrastructure Management Division, you will:support work relating to the operation of TARGET2, TIPS and T2S;coordinate with other stakeholders with a view to ensuring that operational incidents are resolved and minimising the impact on all parties;support the day-to-day operations of clients using the ECB’s TARGET2 component, providing assistance in relation to their participation in the system;draft operational reports and notes on topical matters relating to the governance of TARGET2, TIPS and T2S;contribute to the establishment and maintenance of operational procedures for TARGET2, TIPS and T2S;support project teams responsible for market infrastructure initiatives;support operational testing activities for TARGET2, TIPS and T2S;contribute to the drafting and maintenance of relevant legal and contractual documentation;draft and maintain reports on the compliance of TARGET2, TIPS and T2S with the relevant oversight and regulatory frameworks;liaise with auditors, overseers and regulators, following up on the implementation of action plans in order to comply with their recommendations.This position offers an excellent opportunity to work in a dynamic environment and help to manage some of the world’s largest financial market infrastructure. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens.




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential:a bachelor’s degree or equivalent in finance, business administration, economics, mathematics, physics, computer science or another relevant field (click here for details on degree equivalences);in addition to the above, a minimum of two years’ experience in at least one of the following areas: payments, securities settlement systems, financial services infrastructure, financial market operations, or financial law;good general business and operational knowledge relating to large-value payment and settlement systems, as well as banks’ liquidity management;an understanding of the oversight and legal framework under which payment and securities infrastructure operates;an understanding of the interdependencies between market infrastructure and financial market participants at European and global level;the ability to deliver results within tight time frames, manage multiple assignments, prioritise tasks appropriately, and track the status and progress of numerous processes simultaneously;an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired:a master’s degree in finance, business administration, economics, mathematics, physics, computer science or another relevant field;experience of operating financial market infrastructure;a proven ability to present subject matter in your area of expertise to internal and external audiences in a clear and concise manner.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are motivated to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Working modalities


To enable the Division to cover the normal operating hours of TARGET2 and T2S, and also to maintain its business continuity capability, you will be expected to perform work during non-standard working hours, as well as occasionally working at the ECB’s standby site.




Further information


For additional information on this specific vacancy, you can speak to the hiring manager, Sylvain Debeaumont, on +49 (0)69 1344 6486.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position may include a pre-recorded video interview in the pre-selection phase and – if you are invited to participate in the subsequent selection phase – an on-site written exercise and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Market-Infrastructure-Specialist/2922</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Market Operations/ Financial Risk Analyst</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Market-Operations-Financial-Risk-Analyst/2842</link><description>Fin. Markets &amp; Market Infrastructure Ops - Deadline: 27-Jan-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Market Operations/ Financial Risk Analyst</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Fin. Markets & Market Infrastructure Ops</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i></i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Market Operations</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>27-Jan-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract which may be converted into a permanent contract after three years subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    E/F (1) (minimum monthly net salary €4,167 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Market Ops Policy & Implementation
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Shift?


                                    Yes
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    27.01.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of either the Directorate General Market Operations (DG/M) or potentially the Directorate Risk Management (D/RM). These two business areas cooperate closely on implementing the monetary policy operations of the Eurosystem and controlling any associated risks. They share a strong focus on performing daily tasks at a very high level of reliability under tight time constraints. DG/M has around 180 staff implementing the ECB’s monetary policy, monitoring financial markets and managing the ECB’s financial assets. D/RM has around 50 staff and is responsible for proposing policies and procedures which protect the Eurosystem against financial risks in its monetary policy operations and protect the ECB in its investment and reserve management operations.In your role as a Market Operations Analyst/Financial Risk Analyst, you will be part of a division within DG/M or D/RM of around 30 to 40 members of staff. Depending on the division to which you have applied or been assigned, you will be responsible for supporting one of the following areas of activity:executing Eurosystem credit operations and liquidity management activities, monitoring money market activities and reporting and administrating the euro short-term rate (€STR); managing the ECB’s foreign reserves and own funds, monitoring and reporting on developments in the bond, equity, commodities and foreign exchange markets, and coordinating and implementing the Eurosystem’s asset purchase programmes, foreign exchange interventions and related matters;coordinating nostro reconciliation procedures and legal documentation with counterparties for the ECB’s monetary policy and investment portfolios;monitoring, analysing and assessing developments in the eligibility of assets as collateral and their mobilisation in the context of the Eurosystem collateral framework, as well as in the eligibility of counterparties in the context of the Eurosystem’s monetary policy implementation framework; modelling, analysing and reporting on financial risks, and monitoring the compliance of monetary policy and investment operations with the financial risk control framework, or designing and maintaining the risk management frameworks and policies governing Eurosystem credit operations and non-standard monetary policy measures. All of these roles involve working with advanced IT infrastructures and you will play a role in the ongoing development of these systems. You will work closely with both colleagues in the other divisions of DG/M and D/RM as well as stakeholders inside and outside the ECB. The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a Research Analyst/Market Operations Analyst you will:conduct operational and/or risk management activities with a high degree of accuracy and reliability;combine and aggregate data from multiple sources and prepare analyses and visualisations of relevant market or financial risk developments;support analytical work in your Division, including the preparation of analytical input for the development of the Eurosystem’s monetary policy implementation tools and strategy;present findings at various EU and euro area-level fora;develop and maintain IT applications and tools, working with complex databases of financial and operational data;help develop and automate data management processes to support the wide and timely distribution of reports;coordinate with other business areas on analytical work, systems implementation, database improvements and secure data sharing;document processes and help trainees contribute to the work and objectives of the relevant Division;handle contractual documentation and due diligence activities with financial market counterparties. The position offers you excellent opportunities to leverage your passion for financial markets and to work in a dynamic team with diverse business and technical expertise, collaborating directly with numerous business areas across the ECB as well as with Eurosystem national central banks and market participants. We provide a wide variety of training courses to support you in your further professional development. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential:a bachelor’s degree or equivalent in economics, econometrics, statistics, mathematics, finance, accounting, business administration, computer science, physics or another relevant field (click here for details on degree equivalences);a sound understanding of financial market functioning, financial market developments, market operations or risk management; a solid knowledge of the Eurosystem’s monetary policy implementation / risk management framework and/or experience with the related processes; an in-depth knowledge of Microsoft Office, particularly Excel and PowerPoint;an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired:experience of working in the Eurosystem; professional experience with market information services (e.g. Bloomberg or Reuters);good analytical and econometric skills and a proven ability to collect, organise and analyse large datasets;professional experience in data management, modelling, processing and automation;professional experience using programming languages such as VBA, SQL or Python and data visualisation tools such as Tableau; experience in developing, testing, implementing and maintaining IT applications;professional experience in front/middle/back office and/or accounting, and/or with treasury management systems and/or risk control/analysis in the fields of portfolio management, risk management, settlement, reconciliation and/or financial accounting; experience as a business user of a financial trading platform (e.g. Tradeweb) and/or the SWIFT financial messaging system; experience in handling contractual documentation and due diligence activities (e.g. know your customer, anti-money laundering) with financial market counterparties and knowledge of financial market regulations;a master’s degree and/or professional certification in the area of finance or risk management, e.g. CFA or FRM.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs. You pay attention to detail and deliver high-quality results within tight deadlines.You are motivated to be part of our team and utilise your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Working modalities


To enable your division to cover global market developments and to maintain its business continuity capability, you will occasionally be expected to perform work in shifts as well as during non-standard working hours and to work at the ECB’s standby sites.




Further information


Some of the contracts will be convertible into permanent contracts after three years subject to individual performance and organisational needs.The formal title for positions in DG/M will be Market Operations Analyst, while positions in D/RM carry the title Financial Risk Analyst.For additional information on this specific vacancy, you can speak to Alexander Düring, Adviser in the Bond Market and International Operations Division, on +49 69 13 44 20840.




Application and selection process


The recruitment process for this position will include a pre-recorded video interview in the pre-selection phase and – if you are invited to participate in the subsequent selection phase – a written exercise and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Market-Operations-Financial-Risk-Analyst/2842</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>PhD traineeship in the Directorate General Economics</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/PhD-traineeship-in-the-Directorate-General-Economics/3034</link><description> - Deadline: 11-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>PhD traineeship in the Directorate General Economics</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i></i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i>Students and graduates</i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Economics</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>11-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    PhD traineeship
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals eligible for our traineeship programme (see further information section)
                                



Grant


                                    The trainee grant is €1,970 per month plus an accommodation allowance (see further information section)
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    11.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Business Cycle Analysis (BCA) Division or the Prices and Costs (PAC) Division in the Directorate General Economics of the European Central Bank (ECB). The BCA Division consists of a team of approximately 30 experts and is responsible for analysing and forecasting real macroeconomic developments in the euro area and the largest countries within it. It also conducts sector-specific analyses and economic sentiment surveys of households and non-financial corporations. The Division is currently devoting special attention to the impact of the coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic on business cycle dynamics, with a focus on exploring the use of high-frequency indicators for short-term forecasting, disentangling demand and supply forces and the role of policy support, and identifying transitory and permanent effects of the pandemic on decisions by households and firms.The PAC Division consists of a team of around 20 experts and monitors, analyses and forecasts inflation and its determinants in the euro area and individual countries and sectors within it. This includes assessing the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic and climate change on inflation trends. The Division is a major contributor to the ongoing ECB monetary policy strategy review and plays an important role in the Price-setting Microdata Analysis Network (PRISMA), working with large datasets of prices from various sources, including web-scraping. The Division also assesses inflationary pressures from the external environment and from domestic wage and profit trends, as well as the associated prospects, risks and uncertainties.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a PhD trainee you will:conduct empirical analyses using state-of-the-art economic and econometric models;contribute to the enhancement of analytical, econometric and forecasting tools under the supervision of ECB experts;have the opportunity to submit the resulting papers for publication in the ECB’s Working Paper Series and academic journals.We are looking for PhD trainees to work on several projects in the two divisions.In the BCA Division, key projects will focus on the following issues:investigating the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the euro area household sector using the latest generation of macroeconomic models as individual households face uninsurable earnings risk and inequality in income, wealth and consumption (e.g. Heterogeneous Agent New Keynesian models), with a view to better understanding how differences in structural features of households and firms can shape the transmission of macroeconomic shocks and policies, focusing on the effect of this heterogeneity on aggregate demand and supply;analysing firm-level data for medium-sized firms to assess the impact of COVID-19 on investment and the role of policies, possibly including (1) the impact of illiquidity and insolvency on firms’ investment decisions, and (2) the impact of the type and conditions of external financing on investment decisions, also comparing tangible and intangible investment.In the PAC Division, various projects will focus on the following issues: developing models and/or tools to analyse and forecast wage and price developments and their drivers, including inflation expectations and profit trends, and analysing granular data on prices, wages and corporate balance sheets to better understand the drivers of inflation in the euro area (including the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic and climate change).These positions offer excellent opportunities to build on your skills and track record as an economist by working on state-of-the-art modelling and econometric techniques as well as to contribute to policy work that is of the highest relevance for the economic assessment by the Directorate General Economics. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential: a master’s degree and at least two years of PhD studies in economics, finance, statistics, data science, engineering or a related field;a sound understanding of and theoretical background in macroeconomics and the economic and institutional context in which the ECB fulfils its mandate;excellent knowledge of and a track record in state-of-the-art modelling tools and econometric techniques or data analytics; programming skills in software such as MATLAB, Stata, Python, R, Julia or GAUSS;a good knowledge of the MS Office package;an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired:advanced skills in solving heterogeneous agent models and/or non-linear models;advanced skills in handling micro data (e.g. on firms, households and sectors) and analysing them with microeconometric models and methods;experience in working with macro data and using macroeconometric models, such as structural vector autoregressions (VARs), panel VARs, global VARs, Bayesian VARs and non-linear VARs (time-varying parameters, Markov switching), and conducting co-integration analysis;familiarity with methods for working with big data (e.g. machine learning, web-scraping and text mining) and with distributed computing.You are curious and eager to learn and want to further develop your ability to analyse complex information. You are keen to collaborate with others, pursue team goals and learn from other people’s diverse perspectives. You strive to know and anticipate stakeholder needs and will signal any need for change and propose alternative solutions.You are motivated to contribute to the ECB’s mission, to serve the citizens of the EU as a member of a public institution and to work with colleagues from all over Europe. You are keen to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position.




Further information


PhD traineeship of between 3 and 12 months in total.All trainees will be expected to complete their tasks using their own initiative and to work largely autonomously, under the supervision of an expert. Successful candidates will have access to the ECB’s library, as well as to computing and statistical resources.




Application and selection process


Further information on how to join us is available on our website.The recruitment process for this position will include an online interview via WebEx.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/PhD-traineeship-in-the-Directorate-General-Economics/3034</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Senior Finance Expert</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Senior-Finance-Expert/2885</link><description>Finance and Sourcing - Deadline: 05-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Senior Finance Expert</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i>Finance and Sourcing</i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i></i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Corporate Services, Finance</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>05-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Fixed-term contract which may be converted into a permanent contract after three years subject to individual performance and organisational needs
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals
                                



Salary


                                    F/G (2) (minimum monthly net salary €5,451 and benefits, see further information section)
                                



Role specialisation


                                    Finance and Procurement
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Shift?


                                    Yes
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    05.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Financial Reporting Division in the Directorate Finance. Our Directorate has 110 members of staff and is responsible for financial accounting and reporting, while also carrying out planning and controlling activities, as well as providing cost accounting, procurement and supervisory fee services. Our current focus is on transforming the finance function while maintaining excellence in our daily operations. We use analytical and data visualisation means to support data-driven decisions by thoroughly analysing the information obtained from multiple sources. In this way we actively contribute to the Directorate’s work in producing advanced management information.In your role as Senior Finance Expert you will be part of a team of 28 members of staff responsible for preparing the financial statements and reports of the ECB and the Eurosystem, accounting for the ECB’s financial instruments, and calculating and clearing the Eurosystem national central banks’ (NCBs) monetary income. We produce analytics and forecasts for the decision-making bodies concerning the ECB’s financial situation and results, as well as the Eurosystem’s monetary income. Our team develops and implements standards and policies for the ECB and the Eurosystem in the areas of accounting, financial reporting and monetary income allocation. We work closely with several of the ECB’s business areas, including the Directorate General Market Operations, the Directorate Risk Management and the Directorate General Monetary Policy, as well as with NCBs.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.




Your role


As a Senior Finance Expert, you will:prepare regular and ad hoc financial reports for both the ECB and the Eurosystem (such as the ECB’s quarterly financial results and forecasts, the ECB’s annual accounts, the Eurosystem’s weekly financial statement), analyse financial statements, and perform the Eurosystem NCBs’ monetary income calculations, analysis and forecasting;draft financial reporting policy papers, based on a range of methodological approaches and accounting standards, and you will provide analysis on the ECB’s and the Eurosystem’s financial situation using analytics, modelling and financial data visualisation;prepare related ad hoc briefing notes and presentations for ECB management and business areas, as well as ECB/Eurosystem decision-making bodies;assess the financial impact of various financial operations and implement, from a financial accounting and reporting perspective, any policy decision taken by the ECB and the Eurosystem with regard to monetary policy, foreign exchange and investment portfolios;closely interact, cooperate and share knowledge with other ECB business areas and Eurosystem NCBs on complex dossiers, and prepare quantitative and qualitative assessments on financial accounting and reporting topics in order to support the decision-making process;contribute to the Directorate Finance’s digitalisation, automation and innovation initiatives and to the development and implementation of financial accounting and reporting policies for the ECB and the Eurosystem.The position offers you an excellent opportunity to achieve a comprehensive understanding of the finance function of a central bank by gaining a deep insight into all aspects of financial reporting and related policy matters. It will also enable you to support policymaking and contribute to the credibility of the ECB and the Eurosystem. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens. 




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential: a master’s degree or equivalent in accounting, finance, business administration, economics or another relevant field (click here for details on degree equivalences);in addition to the above, a minimum of seven years’ relevant experience in the field of financial accounting, reporting and policy in a central bank or financial institution; a sound understanding of Eurosystem financial accounting and reporting rules, knowledge of financial instruments and thorough familiarity with international accounting and reporting standards (IFRS);extensive experience in financial statement analysis;experience in preparing high-quality policy documents and briefings, using good policy judgement to address a wide variety of stakeholders including high-level decision-making bodies, combined with competent presentation skills and an ability to communicate complex analytical findings effectively using non-technical terms;a proven track record in extracting, analysing, modelling and visualising financial data in support of decision-making, and hands-on experience in developing and implementing financial forecasting models and dashboards, based on advanced knowledge of Microsoft Office tools, financial reporting applications and/or treasury management systems;an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired: an understanding of the Eurosystem’s monetary income framework;knowledge of financial risks and financial resilience;experience in participating in and presenting to international fora, e.g. ESCB/Eurosystem committees and working groups.You engage collaboratively with others. You pursue team goals and learn willingly from other people’s diverse perspectives. You signal any need for change by explaining it and proposing alternative solutions. You analyse complex information effectively and can evaluate different views to arrive at solutions. You know and anticipate stakeholder needs.You are motivated to contribute to the ECB’s mission, to serve the citizens of the EU as a member of a public institution and to work with colleagues from all over Europe. You are aware of your strengths and areas for development and know what motivates you to perform at your highest level.




Working modalities


To enable the Division to maintain its business continuity capability, you will occasionally be expected to perform work during non-standard working hours and work at the ECB’s standby sites.We are willing to discuss part-time arrangements.




Further information


For additional information on this specific vacancy, you can speak to the hiring manager, Konstantinos Apostolou, on +49 (0)69 13446432 between 14:00 and 17:00 on Friday, 22 January.




Application and selection process


For further information on how to join us, read more.The recruitment process for this position will include a written exercise, a presentation and interviews.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Senior-Finance-Expert/2885</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item><item><title>Traineeship for a perception scientist in the Directorate Banknotes</title><link>https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Traineeship-for-a-perception-scientist-in-the-Directorate-Banknotes/3018</link><description> - Deadline: 09-Feb-2021</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[        <div>
            <h2>Traineeship for a perception scientist in the Directorate Banknotes</h2>
            <p><b>Field: </b><i></i></p>
            <p><b>Level: </b><i>Students and graduates</i></p>
            <p><b>Business Area: </b><i>Banknotes</i></p>
            <p><b>Dealine: </b><i>09-Feb-2021</i></p>
            <br><hr><br>
            <h4>Description</h4>
            General Information






Type of contract


                                    Traineeship
                                



Who can apply?


                                    EU nationals eligible for our traineeship programme (see further information section)
                                



Grant


                                    The trainee grant is €1,070 per month plus an accommodation allowance (see further information section)
                                



Working time


                                    Full time
                                



Place of work


                                    Frankfurt am Main, Germany
                                



Closing date


                                    09.02.2021
                                



Your team


You will be part of the Directorate Banknotes, which seeks to safeguard the integrity of euro banknotes, ensuring that they are an efficient means of payment and protecting them against counterfeiting. Among other things, our Directorate coordinates all banknote development and production activities, both across the Eurosystem and with third parties.You will be working in the New Banknotes (NBN) Section, which is responsible for the design and development of euro banknotes and has a dedicated R&D team that sponsors and monitors activities in the field of banknote R&D. The NBN Section covers all technological aspects of banknotes, working hand in hand with the Directorate’s Anti-Counterfeiting Section and the Production Section.The ECB is an inclusive employer and we strive to reflect the diversity of the population we serve. We encourage you to apply, irrespective of your gender, gender identity, ethnicity, sexual orientation, age, religion, disability or other characteristics.In order to further enhance the diversity of our team, we particularly encourage applications from female candidates.




Your role


As a trainee, you will:contribute to the design, execution and monitoring of testing procedures for new banknotes, assessing their perceptual impact and ease of use (for both individual features and the banknote as a whole) and looking at their overall resilience to counterfeiting;monitor testing activities (such as laboratory tests and on-site production trials) supporting the establishment of specific banknote parameters;help to assess tools and procedures measuring the behavioural, visual and haptic properties of banknotes.This position will offer excellent opportunities to work closely with experts in the fields of banknote development, R&D, communication and counterfeiting. You will be part of a multicultural team that strives for continuous innovation to make a positive impact on the lives of European citizens.




Qualifications, experience and skills


Essential:a bachelor’s degree or higher in applied psychology, neuroscience (or a related field), biophysics, medical biotechnologies or neuromarketing, or any other degree involving specialisation in the field of vision and perception or neuroscience (or a related field);a good knowledge of the MS Office package;an advanced (C1) command of English and an intermediate (B1) command of at least one other official language of the EU, according to the Common European Framework of Reference for Languages.Desired:a master’s degree in applied psychology, the neuroscience of vision and perception, biophysics, medical biotechnologies, neuromarketing or a related field;a good understanding of the statistical methods used to analyse quality control and measurement systems;the ability to keep abreast of new technological developments through active monitoring of scientific publications and other sources of information.You are curious and eager to learn, and want to further develop your ability to analyse complex information. You are keen to collaborate with others, pursue team goals and learn from other people’s diverse perspectives. You strive to know and anticipate stakeholder needs, and will signal any need for change and propose alternative solutions.You are motivated to contribute to the ECB’s mission, to serve the citizens of the EU as a member of a public institution and to work with colleagues from all over Europe. You are keen to be part of our team and to use your skills and competencies to achieve the objectives of this position. 




Further information


Traineeship of between 3 and 12 months in total.When you submit your application, please provide details of any publication history or patents filed in your name.For reasons of confidentiality, work carried out during the traineeship may not be used in any publication, thesis, external research, etc. without specific prior written permission.




Application and selection process


Further information on how to join us is available on our website.The recruitment process for this position will include an online interview via Webex.
        </div>
        ]]></content:encoded><guid isPermaLink="true">https://talent.ecb.europa.eu/careers/JobDetail/Traineeship-for-a-perception-scientist-in-the-Directorate-Banknotes/3018</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 22:42:14 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>